bitcoin a peer-to-peer electronic cash system
比特币是一种点对点电子现金系统
first described in a 2008 white paper authored by the mysterious satoshi
，在 2008 年由神秘的中本
nakamoto the modern financial system relies on our trust of big centralized
聪撰写的白皮书中首次描述 现代金融系统依赖于我们对大型
banks to hold our fiat currencies and execute transactions but trust is a
中央银行的信任来持有我们的法定货币并执行交易，但信任最终是一个
weakness that eventually requires intervention by lawyers and government
弱点 需要律师和政府的干预
bitcoin allows two parties to make reliable transactions
比特币允许两方根据加密证明进行可靠交易
based on cryptographic proof eliminating the need for a trustee middleman
，无需受托
the optimists call it digital gold the pessimists call it fool's gold
中间人 乐观主义者称其为数字黄金悲观者称其为傻瓜黄金，
but in reality it's just software and like all software its purpose is to
但实际上它只是软件，就像所有软件一样，它的目的是
arrange ones and zeros in a meaningful way
以有意义的方式安排 1 和 0
the protocol that makes it meaningful is blockchain which allows two parties to
使其有意义的协议是区块链，它允许两方
engage in transactions denominated in bitcoins
进行以比特币
or satoshi's and just like dollars and cents they have value
或 satoshi 计价的交易，就像美元和美分一样，它们具有价值，
because we believe they do from a financial perspective the blockchain
因为我们相信它们从财务角度来看区块链
is like a shared public ledger that contains all transactions from all
就像一个共享的公共账本，包含所有交易 nsactions 来自所有
bitcoin users and is distributed and synchronized
比特币用户，并
around the world which eliminates the need for a central authority to maintain
在全球范围内分布和同步，这消除了中央机构对其维护
and validate it from a technical perspective think of
和验证的需要从技术角度
the blockchain as a database structured as a linked list where each
将区块链视为一个结构为链表的数据库，其中每个
record or block represents a group of transactions that
记录或块代表一个组
have been permanently committed to the database
对于永久提交到数据库的事务，
it works kind of like a git repo that can never be rebased the important thing
它的工作方式有点像 git repo，永远不会被重新设置基址，重要的
is that each new block is linked to the previous one in the
是每个新区块都与区块链中的前一个区块链接，
blockchain and its creation goes through a very strict set of cryptographic rules
并且它的创建经历了一组非常严格的 加密规则
each user or wallet has a unique public key for receiving money
每个用户或钱包都有一个用于接收
kind of like a username and a unique private key for spending money
资金的唯一公钥（类似于用户名）和一个用于
kind of like a password but before you can spend money you'll need to prove
花钱的唯一私钥（类似于密码），但在您花钱之前，您需要
that you're the owner of a public key that money has been sent to in the past
证明您是所有者过去已向其发送资金的公钥的数量
each transaction contains a hash or encrypted representation
每笔交易都包含上一笔交易的哈希或加密
of the previous transaction and the new owner's public key
表示 找到新所有者的公钥
the hash is then signed with the previous owner's private key
，然后使用前所有者的私钥对哈希进行签名，
this makes it possible to validate the chain of ownership without the need to
这使得无需公开私钥即可验证所有权链，
expose the private key and the signature makes
并且签名使得
it virtually impossible to alter the transaction after it's been
在交易发出后几乎不可能更改交易
issued but what if somebody tries to pay two different people with bitcoin at the
但是，如果有人试图同时用比特币向两个不同的人付款，
exact same time or double spend their money that's where
或者双花他们的钱怎么办？
mining comes in which is a system that allows multiple computers around the
这就是挖矿的用武之地
world to agree on the appropriate state of the
entire system or ledger each new transaction is broadcast to all
每个新交易都被广播到
nodes in the network the transactions are packaged into a
网络中的所有节点 交易被打包到一个
block then miners will expend computing power to validate proof of work
块中，然后矿工将花费计算能力来验证工作量
they compute a proof for a random problem that is very difficult to solve
证明 他们计算一个随机问题的证明，这个问题很难解决，
but very easy to verify the first miner to solve the proof which
但很容易验证第一个问题 矿工解决
happens via dumb luck gets a portion of the bitcoin as a
通过愚蠢的运气发生的证明获得一部分比特币作为
reward the block is then broadcast back to all
奖励，然后广播该块 回到
other nodes where it's permanently confirmed on the blockchain this has
在区块链上永久确认的所有其他节点，这
been bitcoin in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos
已经是 100 秒内的比特币如果您想观看更多这样的短视频，
like this make sure to like and subscribe
请确保喜欢并订阅
and if you really want to learn how blockchain technology works stay tuned
，如果您真的想了解区块链技术的工作原理，请继续关注，
because today we're going beyond 100 seconds to build a blockchain from
因为今天 我们用 node.js 和typescript 从头开始构建区块链的时间超过 100 秒，在
scratch with node.js and typescript and in the process
此过程中，您将
you'll learn all kinds of useful information about cryptography
学习有关密码学的各种有用信息，无论
whether you're into cryptocurrency or not there's many concepts in
您是否喜欢加密货币，密码
cryptography that you should know about as a developer
学中有很多概念是您应该了解的 作为开发人员
things like encryption and signing hashing functions and algorithms like
了解加密和签名哈希函数和算法（如
sha rsa and md5 that make all this stuff
sharsa 和 md5）在接下来的几分钟内使所有这些事情成为
possible over the next few minutes you'll learn
可能，您将
about these concepts by implementing your own blockchain from scratch
通过使用node.js 从头开始实现自己的区块链来了解这些概念
using nothing but node.js and typescript our blockchain will contain wallets
和typescript 我们的区块链将包含钱包
where users can send money back and forth
，用户可以在其中来回汇款
each transaction is added into a block then that block is mined with a proof of
每笔交易都添加到一个块中然后使用
work system at which point it can be added and
工作量证明系统挖掘该块，此时可以在区块
confirmed on the blockchain and throughout this process you'll learn
链上添加和确认它，在整个过程中，您将了解
about all kinds of important concepts and how
各种重要概念以及
they apply to different areas of development
它们如何应用于不同的开发领域
to get started you'll need node.js installed on your system
以开始您 '将需要在您的系统上安装 node.js
then we'll open up vs code to an empty directory run npm init y
然后我们将打开 vs 代码到一个空目录运行 npm init y
to create a new node.js project i'll be using typescript in this code
以创建一个新的 node.js 项目我将在此代码中使用 typescript
because we'll be using object-oriented programming principles to implement the
因为我们将使用对象面向实现
blockchain and having types will just make our code a bit more readable
区块链和类型的编程原则只会使我们的代码更具可读性，
you can install it with npm then create a ts config file
您可以使用 npm 安装它，然后创建一个 ts 配置文件
and copy and paste the values from the main source code from there we can go
并从那里复制并粘贴主源代码中的值，我们可以
into our package json and create a script called dev that runs
进入我们的 打包 json并创建一个名为 dev 的脚本，该脚本运行
the typescript compiler with the watch flag
带有 watch 标志的 typescript 编译器，
to constantly compile our code in the background to plain javascript from
以不断在后台将我们的代码编译为纯 javascript 从
there you should be able to run npm run dev from the command line to
那里你应该能够从命令运行 npm run dev
keep typescript running in the background
保持打字稿在后台运行的行
now we'll write all of our source code in the index cs file
现在我们将在该文件顶部的索引cs文件
at the top of that file we will import the crypto library which is a built-in
中编写所有源代码我们将导入
in node.js as the name implies it's a modular node that handles a bunch of
node.js中内置的加密库，顾名思义它是 一个模块化节点，处理一系列
different functionality for cryptography our simple blockchain implementation
不同的密码学功能我们在这里的简单区块链实现
here has four classes a transaction a block a chain and a
有四个类一个交易 一个区块 一个区块链和一个
wallet let's start by implementing the
钱包让我们从实现交易开始，
transaction which is the fundamental purpose of any cryptocurrency
这是任何加密货币
transfer funds from one user to another user in a transaction
将资金从一个用户转移到另一个用户的基本目的交易中
a transaction object has three properties the amount of the transaction
的用户 交易对象具有三个属性
denominated in bitcoins or fire coins or whatever you want to call your coin
以比特币或火币或任何您想称呼您的硬币的交易
along with the person paying the money and the person receiving the money
金额以及付款人和收款人
eventually we'll set up public keys for these users which you can think of as a
最终我们将设置公钥 对于这些用户，您可以
username that will eventually set as these values in the transaction
将其视为最终将在交易中设置为这些值的用户名，
one final thing we'll do here is add a method to the class to convert the
我们将在这里做的最后一件事是 s在类中添加一个方法来将
object to a string as we go through the tutorial we're
对象转换为字符串，我们将在教程中将
going to serialize everything as strings just to make the cryptographic
所有内容序列化为字符串，以使加密
objects easier to work with and now we're ready to move on to the
对象更易于使用，现在我们准备继续
block implementation a block is like a container for multiple
块实现 块就像一个容器，用于多个
transactions or in our case just a single transaction
事务，或者在我们的例子中只是一个事务，
to keep things simple you can think of a block like an element
以保持简单，您可以将块视为
in an array or more accurately a linked list
数组中的元素或更准确地说是链表，
because each block has a reference or link to the previous block in the chain
因为每个块都有一个引用或链接到 链中
with the previous hash property and that brings up a good cryptographic question
具有前一个散列属性的前一个块，这带来了一个很好的密码学问题
what is a hash a hashing function allows you to take a value of an arbitrary size
什么是散列散列函数允许您获取任意大小的值，
like say a transaction then map it to a value
例如交易，然后将其映射到
with a fixed length like a hexadecimal string the value returned from the
具有固定长度的值 像十六进制字符串一样，从散列函数返回的
hashing function is often called a hash or a hash digest
值通常称为散列或散列摘要，
when you create a hash it cannot be reversed to reconstruct the
当您创建散列时，它无法反转以重建
contents of the original value but what you can do is validate that two values
原始 val 的内容 但是您可以做的是通过比较它们的哈希值来验证两个值
are identical by comparing their hashes and that's
是否相同，这
important for a blockchain because it ensures that two blocks can be linked
对于区块链很重要，因为它确保两个块可以链接
together without being manipulated now to create a hash of a block we're
在一起而无需现在被操纵以创建我们将要实现的块的哈希
going to implement a getter that will first stringify the object
一个getter 将首先对对象本身进行字符串化，
itself then we'll use the create hash function from node crypto
然后我们将使用 node crypto 的 create hash函数，
which specifies a specific hashing algorithm in this case
它在这种情况下指定一个特定的散列算法
sha-256 it stands for secure hash algorithm
sha-256 它代表
with a length of 256 bits it was developed by the nsa back in 2001
长度为 256 位的安全散列算法，它是由 nsa 早在 2001 年
and it's what's known as a one-way cryptographic function
，它就是所谓的单向加密函数
which means that it can encrypt data but it cannot decrypt data back to its
，这意味着它可以加密数据，但不能将数据解密回
original form we can use the function to hash the
原始形式，我们可以使用该函数对块的字符串版本进行哈希处理，
string version of the block then return the hash value or digest as
然后返回哈希值 或摘要
a hexadecimal string and that's all it takes to build a block
为十六进制字符串，这就是构建块所需的全部，
in this case it's a transaction that has a link to the previous
在这种情况下，它是一个交易，它以哈希的形式链接到前一个
transaction in the form of a hash and it also contains a timestamp because
交易，它是 lso 包含一个时间戳，因为
all blocks will be placed in chronological order
所有块都将按时间顺序放置，
now we can move on to the chain which again is like a linked list of blocks
现在我们可以移动到链上，这又是一个块的链表
there should only be one blockchain so we'll go ahead and make it a singleton
，应该只有一个区块链，所以我们将继续通过设置使其成为单例
instance by setting up a static instance property
实例设置一个静态实例属性
that is equal to a new chain instance that'll just ensure that we
，该属性等于一个新的链实例，这将确保我们
have one chain instance instantiated before anything else
先实例化一个链实例，
now we can declare a property for the chain itself which is just an array of
现在我们可以为链本身声明一个属性，它只是
blocks in the constructor we'll define the
构造函数中的一组块，我们' 将定义
first block in the chain which is called the genesis block
链中的第一个块，称为创世
the previous hash is null because there's nothing for it to link to
块，前一个哈希为空，因为它没有任何链接，
then it instantiates a new transaction that transfers a hundred coins to
然后它实例化一个新的交易，将一百个硬币转移到中本
satoshi notice how we're creating money out of
聪注意我们是如何从稀薄中创造货币的
thin air here that's no different than when the central bankers or federal
这里的空气与中央银行家或美联储
reserve turn on the money printer now in the blockchain class we'll often
现在在区块链类中打开货币打印机时没有什么不同，我们经常
need to grab the last block in the chain so we'll go ahead and create a getter to
需要抓住链中的最后一个块，所以 我们将继续创建一个 getter 来
help us out with that then we'll define a new method named add
帮助我们解决这个问题，然后我们将定义一个名为 add block 的新方法
block that takes a transaction the sender's public key and a signature
，该方法接受交易发送者的公钥和签名
that we can verify before adding a new block to the chain a
，我们可以在将新块添加到链之前验证该签名
naive and simple implementation might look like this
天真和简单的实现可能看起来像这样
we instantiate a new block taking the last block's hash and this new
我们实例化一个新块，获取最后一个块的哈希和这个新
transaction then we push that new block onto the
交易，然后我们将该新块推送到链上，
chain but the problem is that there's no way to know that this is a legitimate
但问题是没有办法知道这是
transaction anybody could send arbitrary transaction
任何人都可以发送的合法交易 任意交易
data to transfer coin to someone else we can allow people
数据将硬币转移给其他人 我们可以允许人们
to securely send coin back and forth by implementing a wallet
通过实施钱包来安全地来回发送硬币，钱包
which is essentially just a wrapper for a public key and a private key
本质上只是公钥和私钥
the public key is for receiving money the private key is for spending money
的包装器 公钥用于接收资金 私钥用于
to generate a public and private key we're going to use a different algorithm
花钱生成公钥和私钥我们将使用一种称为 rsa 的不同算法
called rsa which stands for the names of the guys
，它代表创建它的人的名字
that created it and unlike sha this is a full encryption algorithm
，与 sha 不同，这是一个 完整的加密算法
that can encrypt data and then decrypt it if you have the
，可以加密数据然后解密它，如果你有
proper key to do so to encrypt a value you would use the public key to convert
适当的密钥来加密一个值，你将使用公钥将
it to ciphertext which is an unreadable version of the original value then you
其转换为密文，这是原始值的不可读版本，然后你
would use the private key to decrypt it back to its original form
将使用私有将其解密回原始形式的密钥，
but what we're actually more interested in is using the key pair to create a
但我们实际上更感兴趣的是使用密钥对创建带有
digital signature with signing we don't need to encrypt
签名的数字签名，我们不需要
the message but instead create a hash of it we then sign the hash with our
加密消息，而是创建它的哈希，然后我们签署 使用我们的私钥散列，
private key then the message can be verified later
然后可以稍后使用公钥验证消息，
using the public key if anybody tried to change the message it would produce a
如果有人试图更改消息，它将产生
different hash in which case the verification would fail
不同的散列，在这种情况下，验证将失败
and that's really important for a coin because if we didn't have a signature
，这对于硬币来说非常重要，因为如果我们没有 一个签名，
then someone could intercept the transaction message and change the
然后有人可以拦截交易消息并更改
amount or change the payee with no way to detect that anything was
金额或更改收款人
out of the ordinary now when generating the key pair with
，而现在在生成密钥对时无法检测到任何异常情况 h
node crypto i'm going to format them as strings
node crypto 我要将它们格式化为字符串
and to do that i'm going to add some extra options here for encoding the
，为此我将在此处添加一些额外的选项来进行编码
important one to know is the format pem which you would
normally save to a file on the user's computer system where it
could be reused in the future now that we have a public key and
既然我们有公钥和
private key we can use it to send money to another user
私钥，将来可以重用它，我们可以使用它向另一个用户汇款，
the way we do that is by specifying an amount and the public key
我们这样做的方式是指定金额和
of the user being paid we can then use node crypto to create a signature
被支付用户的公钥，然后我们可以 使用节点加密再次创建签名
again an sha 256 format using the transaction data as the value
使用交易数据作为值的 sha 256 格式
we can then create a signature by signing it with a private key
然后我们可以通过使用私钥对其进行签名来创建签名
this is kind of like creating a one-time password it allows us to verify our
这有点像创建一次性密码 它允许我们验证我们的
identity with the private key without actually having to expose the private
身份 使用私钥而实际上不必公开
key the signature depends on both the transaction data and the private key
私钥签名取决于交易数据和私钥，
but it can be verified as authentic using the public key we can now attempt
但可以使用公钥验证它是真实的，我们现在可以尝试
to add that block to the blockchain by passing the transaction
将该块添加到区块链中
the public key and the signature in real life those values would be transferred
在现实生活中传递交易公钥和签名这些值将通过互联网传输
over the internet then the signature could be verified
然后可以验证签名
let's go ahead and refactor the add block method
让我们继续并重构
in the chain class it'll use node crypto to create a signature verification
链类中的添加块方法它将使用节点加密来创建签名验证
then pass the same transaction data to the verifier we can then validate it
然后将相同的交易数据传递给验证者，然后我们可以
by verifying that the transaction data has not been tampered with
通过
using the sender's public key and the signature itself
使用发送者的公钥和签名本身验证交易数据没有被篡改
and we're now able to securely verify that that user is actually trying to
来验证它，我们现在能够安全地验证该用户实际上是在尝试
spend that amount of money to the other user
把这么多钱花给另一个用户，
but there's still one more big issue with our blockchain and that is the
但我们的区块链还有一个更大的问题，那就是
double spend issue imagine the spender tried to send money
双重支付问题，想象一下消费者试图
to two different users at the same time they could potentially spend more money
同时向两个不同的用户汇款，他们可能会花费比实际更多的钱
than they actually own before their transaction is confirmed on the
在他们的交易在区块链上确认之前拥有
blockchain the way bitcoin addresses that issue is
比特币解决该问题的方式是
with a proof of work system which requires
使用工作量证明系统，该系统要求 要求
each new block to go through a process called mining where a difficult
每个新块通过一个称为挖掘的过程，在该过程
computational problem is solved in order to confirm the block
中解决了一个困难的计算问题以确认该块，
but it's very easy to verify that work by multiple other nodes on the system
但是当挖掘分布在世界各地时，很容易验证系统上多个其他节点的工作，
when mining is distributed around the world it means you have multiple nodes
这意味着你有 多个节点
competing to confirm a block on the blockchain and
竞争确认区块链上的一个区块，
works like a big lottery the winner of the lottery earns a portion of the coin
并像大彩票一样工作 彩票中奖者获得一部分硬币
as incentive which motivates people to invest in the
作为激励，激励人们投资
computing resources to mine a coin and also to pump the price of the coin
计算资源以开采硬币并提高价格 硬币
higher and higher because the higher the price the more money you make
越来越高，因为价格越高，你赚的钱就越多，
you can think of it like converting cloud computing resources into money
你可以把它想象成现在将云计算资源转化为
now to implement a basic proof of work system we'll go back into our block
金钱来实现一个基本的工作量证明系统，我们将回到我们的块
class and add a nonce value which is a
类并添加一个 nonce 值 是
one-time use random number then in the chain class we'll add a
一次性使用的随机数，然后在链类中我们将添加一个
method called mine that takes that nonce as an argument
名为 mine 的方法，该方法将该随机数作为
what this method will do is attempt to find a number that when added to the
参数，该方法将尝试查找 一个数字，当添加到
nonce will produce a hash that starts with
nonce 时将产生一个以四个零开头的哈希
four zeros the only real way to figure out that value is with brute force by
找出该值的唯一真正方法是通过
creating a while loop that goes digit by digit
创建一个 while 循环，逐位运行，
until we find the requested value to handle the brute force computation
直到我们找到处理暴力的请求值强制计算
we'll create a while loop that creates a hash with the md5 algorithm
我们将创建一个 while 循环，它使用 md5 算法创建一个散列
it's very similar to sha-256 but is only 128 bits
它与 sha-256 非常相似，但只有128 位
and is faster to compute we'll continue to create new hashes
并且计算速度更快 我们将继续
inside the while loop until we find one that starts with four zeros
在 while 循环中创建新的散列，直到我们找到一个
when we find it we can return the solution and then send it off to other
当我们找到它时从四个零开始，我们可以返回解决方案，然后将其发送到
nodes where it can be verified and the block can finally be confirmed
可以验证的其他节点，并且最终可以在区块
on the blockchain and that takes care of our blockchain implementation
链上确认该块，如果我们继续下去，它会负责我们的区块链
if we go down to the example usage here you can see we instantiate a few wallets
实施 这里的示例用法你可以看到我们为不同的用户实例化了几个钱包
for different users then allow those users to send money to
然后允许这些用户
each other using their various public keys
使用他们的各种公钥相互汇款，
if we go ahead and log out the chain itself you can see we have a bunch of
如果我们继续注销链本身，你可以 看到我们有一堆基于前一个块的哈希
blocks or transactions linked to each other
相互链接的块或交易
based on a hash of the previous block now this blockchain is obviously not
现在这个区块链显然不是
perfect and something that i just hacked
完美的，我只是一起破解了一些东西
together to teach you the gist of how a blockchain works
来教你区块链如何工作的要点
feel free to grab the full source code on github if you learned something in
随意抓住github 上的完整源代码如果您在此过程中学到了一些东西，
the process please make sure to like and subscribe
请确保喜欢并订阅
and consider sending me some bitcoin or sponsoring me on github for just one
并考虑向我发送一些比特币或在 github 上赞助我，每月只需 1
dollar a fiat per month i use all that income to sponsor other
美元一个法定货币我用所有的收入来赞助其他
developers myself thanks for watching and i will see you
开发人员自己感谢 看，我会在下一个见到你
in the next one